I feel the same for Tatsumi too.
達海さんも同じだと思うぜえ？
あの人なりの考えがあるんだろうよ
He also has his way of thinking.
あれが遊びだってんなら　きっと遊びでなきゃいけない
Using that kind of game to determine the starting line-up.
理由があるはずなんだ
I feel that Tatsumi is that kind of a person.
おれ俺は　達海さんは　そういう人だと思うぜ　根拠はないけどな
Though it's only my feelings.
Dori...
ドリさん
I still have something to ask you.
ドリさんに　もう一つ聞きたいことがあるんスけど
今回もスタメン争奪ゲム大会を行います
We will now also conduct a competition to determine the starting line-up.
ええっまた
Again?
あくまで参考だよ　参考それがすべてじゃないよン
That was only a reference.
The end product is not everything.
That's about all I can take...
やってられっか
おい　クロ！
Hey, Kuro!
最悪だ冗談じゃなく
This is bad. It's no joke. Things really are turning for the worse.
最悪の展開になっちまった
試合に出たくないヤツはやんなくていいよ
Those who don't feel like playing the next match are allowed to not participate.
However, those who want to win the next game...
ただ　試合に出て勝ちたいヤツは
ガキみたいに一生懸命　遊ぶこと！
Go ahead and enjoy the competition!
United we stand, Fly a flag!
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ 風を受け止めて」
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand, Fly a flag!
「Ｕｎｉｔｅｄ　ｗｅ　ｓｔａｎｄ，　Ｆｌｙ　ａ　ｆｌａｇ たなびけ勝利のｆｌａｇ」
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
「遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けて」
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
「日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ」
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
「汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め」
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
「何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける」
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
「夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ」
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
「Ｌｅｔ’ｓ　ｓｔａｒｔ　ｎｏｗ ＧＩＡＮＴ　ＫＩＬＬＩＮＧ」
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
「ｆｏｒ　ｔｈｅ　ｒｉｇｈｔ ｈｏｌｄ　ｏｎ　ｔｉｇｈｔ」
For the right! Hold on tight!
「ｍｙ　ｓｔｏｒｙ…」
My story...
Forever...
「ｆｏｒｅｖｅｒ」
Damn...
There's no need for you to skip training together with me.
お前まで　練習バックれることなかったんだよ！
出場停止の上　罰金だぞ　罰金出場給も　もらえねえしよ
You'll get fined and banned from playing. Banned!
There won't be any appearance bonuses for you too.
Money's not the issue here.
金なんてどうでもいいだろ
It's not being able to play that is so much more unbearable.
試合に出られないことのほうが…痛い
That asshole...
あの野郎　カップ戦の大事な初戦だってのに
The opening match of the Japan Cup is such a big game! Doesn't he want to win?
勝ちたくねえのかよコシさんほどじゃねえけどよ
Though I'm nothing compared to Koshi, but I have always wanted this team to win.
俺は　このチムを勝たせたいと思って　やってきたんだ
And I give my all.
それなりに必死によぉ
I'm neither as tall as you nor good in techniques,
俺は　スギみてえにデカくねえしテクニックも　ねえからよ
Which is why I compensate with guts and an undying attitude to snatch the ball.
当たりで負けねえのとがむしゃらにボルを奪うこと
そこだけは　チムで一番の選手を目指してきた
I have always played with these qualities in order to be an integral member of the squad.
I know.
知ってるよ
Though we've had a number of inept managers before,
今までも　能無しの監督はいたけどよ
勝ちてえと思ってるヤツを道楽で外す監督なんざ…
I have never actually seen one who would bring off players who wanted to win just because he doesn't like them!
１人もいなかったってんだよ！
What's with him? He startled me.
何だよびっくりするなぁ
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
Calm down, Kuro.
落ち着けって　クロ
俺はお前の　　その　とんでもない熱さが　うらやましいよ
I admire that hot, passionate side of yours.
あぁ？クロみたいな闘志むき出しの選手は
A combative player such as you will surely be a threat to any opponent.
相手にとって脅威に決まってるそれを必要としない監督なんて
You are a player that no manager would say they wouldn't need.
いるわけがない実際に　いただろ
I was just speaking the truth.
Alright, hear me out.
まあ聞けって俺　ドリさんに聞いたんだ
I approached Dori for his opinions.
何を？俺らが出なかった前回の試合と
Of what?
I asked him about the previous match that we were not called up for,
俺らが出てた　その前の試合後ろから見てて　どう違ったか
As well as the match before that.
How does he feel about being protected by two different defensive pairings?
うん　どう違うかはい
How I felt?
Yes.
まあ　そりゃ　前の試合は急に若手が起用されたから
Well, the decision was a sudden one,
危なっかしさは確かにあった
Therefore there were certain risks.
でも　機能してる感じはあったな
However,
Those youngsters did produce the desired effects.
逆に　お前たちの場合は時間が止まってるんだよ
Conversely, when you two were up there,
It just feels like time has stopped for you.
チムが前に進んでるのにお前たちは　それでいいのか？
The team is moving forward, yet the two of you lagging behind. Is that fine with you?
ああ？　意味わかんねえクロ
I don't have a clue about what you're saying!
Kuro...
Japan Cup Preliminaries Round 1
ETU vs Shimizu Impulse
Sumidagawa Stadium
ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！
インパルス！　インパルス！
やっぱりさあ…うん？
As I expected...
問題は　俺たちのディフェンスラインなんだよ
The problem lies in our defense line.
ケッ　またそれかい　だからやってんじゃねえか　俺らはよ！
You're still going on with that? Didn't I mention that our performance was fine!
きちんと上げるところは上げてるしよ
When we were needed in offense, we helped out too!
Don't keep harping on what Akasaki said, Sugi!
赤崎みてえなこと言うなよ　スギ！…あ？
何よりの違いはさ俺たちが出た２試合は無得点で
The difference was that the team was unable to score in the two matches that we've played in.
この前の試合は　世良がゴル決めてるってことだ
In addition, Sera even scored during the previous game.
あぁ？同じ負け試合でも前回のほうが
Both the games ended with losses, but they were able to defend, as well as play better.
コンパクトで　いいサッカしてたう…
Though Kobayashi and Kamei were worried about the opponents breaking through,
小林と亀井は　後ろ抜かれることにビビりながらも
They still kept a high line...
ディフェンスラインを高く保ってた
だから　中盤のスペスが小さくなる短いパスが　どんどん回せる
This narrows down the space we expose in the midfield area, while allowing us to assist with simple passes.
攻撃のパタンも増えるチャンスも多くなる
This heightens our attacking prowess.
And we're able to create more chances.
ジノだ！
It's Gino!
Tsubaki!
椿！行ける！
You can do it!
あ！　判断遅いよ　椿！
Your decision-making's too slow, Tsubaki!
Beware of their counter!
カウンタ注意！クソ…
Damn it!
What happened, Baki?
バッキ　どうしたんだい？
さっきと同じつぶされ方じゃないか
You fell for the same trick back there.
I'm sorry.
すいませんそこ２人　守備！
Two more men! Cover up!
Geez, your ignorance made you look like a cute idiot.
以前はバカみたいに単純でかわいらしかったのに
Still can't get over your mistakes during the pre-season game?
ひょっとしてプレシズンマッチの失敗
まだ引きずってるんじゃなかろうね
That's not it!
違います！
ま　どちらにせよ　従順じゃない犬に　いつまでも餌を与えるほど
Well, anyway, I don't have much patience for a dog that I have to constantly spoon-feed. Understood?
僕は気長な性格じゃないよ覚えておくように
I must stop giving the team any more troubles!
これ以上チムに迷惑かけられない
I need to do something. Anything!
何とかしなきゃ…　何とか
もう一歩ってところまで行くんですがねぇ
He was almost through, and yet...
うん…　やっぱり駄目ですかねぇ椿は
Guess he's still not up to it, that Tsubaki.
Just let him be.
いいよ　あいつはああ？
そんなに期待してないしえ？
It's not like I expected much from him.
あいつはピッチの中で答えを見つけるほうがいい
Just let him find his own answers on the pitch.
もう少し様子を見るそれより今の問題は　あっち
We'll just take it as we go.
Right now, the real problem is that side.
亀井と小林が　このチャンスをものにするか　それとも…
Will Kobayashi and Kamei grab their chances?
Or,
Will the two rebels be able to find their own answers off the pitch?
デコボココンビが　ピッチの外から答えを見つけるか
さあて　どうなる？そろそろ時間切れだぞ
How will things develop? Time's almost up.
Ever since Tatsumi took over as manager,
達海さんが監督になってこのチムは変わった
This team has started to change.
All he did was change the line-up of the team, though the way we approach the game is still the same,
単にスタメンが変わったからか意識の変化かは　わからないけど
以前より走る攻撃的なサッカになった
And this team has played even better than before.
During the match against Victory, we were playing well for a period of time,
ヴィクトリ戦は　俺たちもその流れに乗れた
You would've noticed it too, Kuro.
本当は気づいてんだろ？クロ開幕戦の１点目
That first goal during the opening game,
あのゴルで俺たちは腰が引けたんだ
We cowered and dropped off from that initial shot.
なに？あんなのラッキゴルだ
What?
That was only a lucky goal.
すぐに切り替えなきゃいけなかった　なのに…
We should've forgotten about it right after that.
Instead...
俺たちは不安に駆られてゴル前にへばりついてたんだ
We became uneasy and stuck ourselves in front of goal.
去年までと同じように
Just like what we did last year.
いや　俺らはちゃんと…頭で思ってただけだ
That's not it! We were just...
We only had it in our heads, but our bodies didn't carry it out.
体は反応してないあ…
前回の試合　ベンチから見ててやっと気づいた
I looked over from the bench during the last game...
ドリさんの位置がいつもより前だったんだ
I noticed that Dori positioned himself further up than before.
He had lots of opportunities to take control of the ball in the penalty area,
ドリさんが　ペナルティエリアの外でボルをタッチする機会が多かった
This is evidence that the defense line has been pushed up.
ディフェンスラインが上がってるってことの何よりの証拠だ
This team is gradually moving forward,
チムが前へ行こうとしてるのに俺たちだけ引いて守ってりゃ
Yet, both of us are remained in our comfort zone, which in turn, exposed the space in front of us.
そりゃ　スペスもできる
It's exactly like what the manager, coach, Akasaki and Dori said.
監督やコチ　赤崎やドリさんの言うとおりだ
俺たちは変わってない変わった気になってるだけだ
We didn't change at all.
We only thought that we changed.
So what now, Kuro?
どうする？　クロ　このままじゃ若手にポジション取られるぜ
If this goes on, our position will be taken away by the youngsters!
監督が変わったからって選手が変わるわけじゃない
Though the manager has changed, the players are still in the same formation.
はあ俺たちが　まず戦わなきゃいけないのは
The initial opponents that we have to defeat...
敵チムじゃない
...is not the opposing teams.
自分たちだ
It's ourselves.
このチムに根づいてる負け癖その根っこは深いよ
This team's 'losing culture'...
...runs deep into the veins.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
１試合ごとに　切り替えができるようにならなきゃ
If the players can't understand the manager's decision to rotate them after a game, they won't last the season.
シズンは　とても戦えねえ
切り替えって　まさか　あのゲムってそのためにやってたんですか？
Rotation? So that was your objective when you organized that game competition?
Didn't I tell you?
え？　言ったじゃん　俺聞いてませんよ　ひと言も！
I've never heard that before! Not once!
Why do you tell us these important details only after everything's done?
なんで監督は　いつもそういう大事なことを…
あっ？え？
そ　そんな…
N-No way!
ＰＫか？
A penalty?
ドリ！　ドリ！　ドリ！
Though Kamei's marking was tight, he was a little too eager.
亀井は粘ったけどねぇ…若さが出た
Dori.
ドリ　頼むぜ
It's all up to you.
ドリ！　ドリ！ドリ！　ドリ！
Dori...
ドリさん…　２年前まで一緒にプレしてただけに
It's been two years since we last played together...
I'm a bit reluctant.
やりづれえな
ドリさん…
Dori...
It's saved!
止めた！詰めさせんな！
The follow-up!
亀井！させんじゃねえ！
Kamei!
Stop him!
あ　もったいない！
We were so close!
す…　すいません…ドリさん
I'm sorry, Dori...
切り替え　切り替え！点取りに行くぞ！
Forget about it! We need to score!
Don't let your heads down! Defend from the front!
このまま終わるな！前からプレスかけて　ボル奪え！
ドリさん…
Dori...
This cannot happen again.
これ以上…　ドリさんに恥かかせらんねえな
We shouldn't embarrass Dori anymore.
Kuro...
クロ
We'll have to give it a shot, damn it.
やってやるよコンチキショ
Is that so?
あ　そうか　はぁ　駄目だねえ全く　…おう　そんじゃあね
That's not good! Bye then.
Who was that?
誰？八百屋の吾郎だよ注文の件でよ
It's the grocery store owner. He called for an order.
He then went to watch a soccer game.
そしたら　サッカ見てきたって言うんだけどよ
But they lost again!
また負けたって言うんだよ　ＥＴＵいつまでたっても弱いねえ　ッタク
ETU.
It's been so many years, and they are still such a weak team!
Dear, I thought you weren't interested in soccer?
お父さんサッカ興味ないでしょうにそらまあ　さっぱりだけどよ
I'm still not interested, but it's only natural that I want the local team to win!
地元のチムには勝ってほしいってもんだろうがよ
Here! Thanks for waiting!
ほい　お待ちどう！たんと食えよ
Enjoy your food!
Let's finish this up quickly and leave.
早く食って出るかフフン
おっちゃん　うめえよ期待してなかったけど
Old man, your ramen is fantastic! Though I wasn't so sure initially...
おいおい　トゲのある褒め方だねま　許す　ハハハハ！
So are you complimenting me or dissing me?
Whatever, I'll forgive you.
What an annoying old man.
うるせえ　じじいだぜ
何せ　ラメン一筋　５０年だからよそこらの店とは
Well, I have been honing my skills for the past fifty years.
Compared to other stores, my pair of hands is certainly different from theirs!
ここが違うのよ　ここが！
へえ　５０年か　大したもんだねぇいやあ　よくつぶれなかったね
Fifty years? That's amazing!
It's quite a feat that your business could last that long.
ヘン　またトゲのある言い方だねま　いろいろあるけどよ
You have thorns in your words again.
Well, there were ups and downs from time to time; it's important to look at the bright side of things.
やっぱり　前向きにやんのがコツだな　イマイチなラメン作ったら
If you've failed to produce a good bowl of ramen, you just have to try again.
次　うまいの作りゃいいんだ今日が駄目なら明日ってな
If you failed today, just try again tomorrow!
あ…切り替えってことかい？
So we should just forget about our failures?
そう　前向きに切り替えよ　切り替え
That's right! Just forget about them!
Forget!
後ろ向きになっちまうのが一番よくねえな
Getting depressed isn't the way to go. All you need is to take it easy!
バカなくらいがちょうどいいんだよ
そこのにいちゃんたち向いてそうだな　この店　継ぐか？
The two gentlemen over there look quite capable. Wanna take over my shop?
毎度ありがとうございます
Thanks for your patronage!
何だか耳の痛い話だったな
My ears are producing wax just from listening to his lecture.
二度と来るか
Who would wanna go back?
ふあ
Alright.
おううん？
昨日も負けやがって　またあのバカげた遊び　やんのかよ
We lost again yesterday.
Are you still going to play that childish game?
ひょっとして　やりたくなった？ちげち　違えよ　コラ！
So you're interested?
Of course not, dammit! It's not like I'm doing it for your sake!
テメエのためじゃねえぞ俺は何であろうと
I just hate losing to someone! You understand?
負けんのが気に食わねえだけだ！分かったか！
クロ　必死すぎ
Kuro...
You're going overboard.
ふん…
何とか言えよ
W-What? Say something.
No matter how good a strategy is, if you can't have possession of the ball, it's still all talk.
どんなに攻撃的な戦術だろうがボル奪わなきゃ何もできねえ
フットボルは常に　ディフェンスから始まる
Football starts from its defense.
だから　ＥＴＵのフットボルもお前たちから始まる
Therefore, ETU's football starts from the two of you.
期待してるよディフェンス陣
I'm expecting great things from you, defense team!
Japan Cup Preliminaries Round 2
FC Sapparo vs ETU
Second Half
We can do it!
行ける！
Long ball!
ロングボル…９番ケア！
No.9, Kia!
うわ　体力落ちてない！なに大丈夫　見えてる見えてる
He's not wearing down at all!
What? It's alright. He's starting to wear out.
ファウルすんなよ　クロ！
Don't commit a foul again, Kuro!
おりゃ！
おうおう　どうした！全然焦ってねえぞ　おりゃ！
What's that? I wasn't being impulsive at all!
よし　いいぞ　クロ！ナイスクリア！
Okay, nice one, Kuro! Nice clear!
That was close!
いや　危ねえ　危ねえ  焦ってたんじゃん
He was panicking.
うん　吹っ切れましたかねこの間のサッカテニスも
Looks like he's finally listening. And he was also participating in the Soccer-Tennis game!
張り切ってたし今日は　ディフェンスラインを高く保って
The defense is solid today. Our game is finally coming together!
コンパクトなサッカを実践できてる集中してますよ　黒田と杉江
Both Kuroda and Sugi are really concentrating.
That said though, the problem now is whether or not they can maintain their performance if anything bad were to happen.
とはいえ問題はこの先　何か起きた時に
この状態を保てるかですよね
まあまあ　俺たちまっやることはやったよ　松ちゃん
You can say so, but we've done all we can, Macchan.
あと　できることって言ったらさあいつらを信じることだけでしょ
The only thing we can do now...
...is to believe in them.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！
Is that all you've got? You guys can do better than that!
おいおい！　そんなもんかよ！まだ声出せんだろ！
今日だけは負けられねえんだ！声出せ！
We can't lose today! Cheer louder!
ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！
Set-pieces. This is where we really need to be focusing hard!
セットプレ…　ここ集中だぞ
おい引っ張ってる　引っ張ってる
Spread out! Spread out!
マク確認しろ！　確認！
Mark your man!
気を付けろよ　お前ら！　ここまでいいゲム運び　してんだからよ！
You guys be careful! We've been playing well since the start!
It's into the box!
ファだ！
オライ！　…あ
Mine!
How can we concede at this kind of time? Damn it!
この時間にか！クソ！
I screwed up.
やっちまった…　俺のマクだ
I was supposed to mark him!
石浜！　下向くんじゃねえ！こっからだ　こっから！
Ishihama!
Don't let your head down! We're only starting!
That was due to a set play, not a breakdown in our defense!
セットプレからの失点だ　ディフェンスが完全に崩されたわけじゃない！
Come on, walk with your heads held high!
行くぞオラ！　上を向いて歩け！あ…　はい
Yes!
Alright! That's the way!
おし！　それでよし！戦えるチムになってきた！
You've become a capable team!
Let's pull it back! Our defense's not conceding another!
よし　盛り返して行くぞ！ディフェンスのライン　上げてくぞ！
ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！
You've got find the way to believe
「Ｙｏｕ’ｖｅ　ｇｏｔ　ｆｉｎｄ　ｔｈｅ　ｗａｙ　ｔｏ ｂｅｌｉｅｖｅ，　ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ　ａｎｄ　ｃａｒｒｙ　ｏｎ」
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
「Ｔｉｌｌ　ｙｏｕ　ｃａｎ　ｓｅｅ ｔｏｍｏｒｒｏｗ， Ｉ’ｌｌ　ｓａｙ　“ｎｅｖｅｒ　ｌｏｏｋ　ｂａｃｋ”」
I'll say “never look back”
「追い風を待って そうｃｈａｎｃｅを のがすなら」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
「自分が風になれ　ｎｏ　ｆｅａｒｓ， ｎｏ　ｔｅａｒｓ，　ｙｅｓ　Ｌｅｔ　ｉｔ　ｇｏ！」
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！） Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
「限界追い越せ 行け　キツイほど ｈｅａｒｔ　ｉｎ　ｒｅｄ」
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！ （Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！） Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
「あすは見えない　だから」
「Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ やめられない」
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！ Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！　Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！」
Get tough!
「Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｇｏｌｄ！） Ｇｅｔ　ｔｏｕｇｈ！（Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）」
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
「共に乗り越えて　行け 見えるか　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｄａｙｂｒｅａｋ　ｔｈｅｒｅ」
mieruka It's daybreak there
見えるか It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
「Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！（Ｓｔａｙ　ｃｏｏｌ！）　Ｇｏ　ｏｎ！ （Ｗｅ’ｌｌ　ｇｏ！）　予測できない」
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
「だから　Ｉｔ’ｓ　ｔｉｍｅ　ｔｏ　ｇｏ 止められない」
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
Is it because of me that we can't win?
We'll meet up ten minutes later at Gate W-1!
Bad news! The fans...
Just wait and see, Nagoya!
I'm going to smash you to bits!
Pepe!